<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
        <string name="wawel_short_description">The Wawel Castle is a castle residency located in central Krakow, Poland.
                Built at the behest of King Casimir III the Great, it consists of a number of structures situated around
                the Italian-styled main courtyard.</string>

        <string name="wawel_long_description">The castle, being one of the largest in Poland,
                represents nearly all European architectural styles of medieval, renaissance and baroque periods.
                The Wawel Royal Castle and the Wawel Hill constitute the most historically and culturally significant site in the country.
                In 1978 it was declared a UNESCO World Heritage Site as part of the Historic Centre of Kraków.
                For centuries the residence of the kings of Poland and the symbol of Polish statehood,
                the Castle is now one of the country’s premier art museums. Established in 1930,
                the museum encompasses ten curatorial departments responsible for collections of paintings,
                including an important collection of Italian Renaissance paintings, prints, sculpture, textiles,
                among them the Sigismund II Augustus tapestry collection, goldsmith’s work, arms and armor, ceramics,
                Meissen porcelain, and period furniture. The museum’s holdings in oriental art include the largest collection
                of Ottoman tents in Europe. With seven specialized conservation studios, the museum is also an important center
                for the conservation of works of art.</string>

        <string name="mariacki_short_description">Church of Our Lady Assumed into Heaven (also known as Saint Mary\'s Church)
                is a Brick Gothic church adjacent to the Main Market Square in Kraków, Poland.</string>

        <string name="mariacki_long_description">Built in the 14th century, its foundations date back to the early 13th century
                and serve as one of the best examples of Polish Gothic architecture. Standing 80 m (262 ft) tall, it is particularly
                famous for its wooden altarpiece carved by Veit Stoss (Wit Stwosz). On every hour, a trumpet signal—called the
                Hejnał mariacki—is played from the top of the taller of Saint Mary\'s two towers. The plaintive tune breaks off
                in mid-stream, to commemorate the famous 13th century trumpeter, who was shot in the throat while sounding the
                alarm before the Mongol attack on the city. The noon-time hejnał is heard across Poland and abroad broadcast live
                by the Polish national Radio 1 Station.</string>

        <string name="mound_short_description">Kościuszko Mound (Polish: kopiec Kościuszki) in Kraków, Poland, erected by Cracovians
                in commemoration of the Polish national leader Tadeusz Kościuszko, is an artificial mound.</string>

        <string name="mound_long_description">A serpentine path leads to the top, approx. 326 metres (1,070 ft) above sea level, with a panoramic
                view of the Vistula River and the city. It was completed in November 1823. The location selected for the monument was the natural
                Blessed Bronisława Hill (Polish: Wzgórze bł. Bronisławy), also known as Sikornik, situated in the western part of Kraków\'s Zwierzyniec District.
                Kościuszko Mound is one of Kraków\'s four memorial mounds, consisting of two prehistoric mounds, Krakus Mound and Wanda Mound, and two modern ones,
                Piłsudski Mound and Kościuszko Mound.</string>

        <string name="museum_short_description">The National Museum in Kraków, popularly abbreviated as MNK, established in 1879, is the main branch of Poland\'s
                National Museum, which has several independent branches with permanent collections around the country.</string>

        <string name="museum_long_description">The Museum consists of 21 departments which are divided by art period; 11 galleries, 2 libraries, and 12 conservation
                workshops. It holds some 780,000 art objects, spanning from classical archeology to modern art, with special focus on Polish painting.</string>
</resources>